[Music]
hey
hey hey hey
[Music]
hey well good morning and welcome to the
fiber Broadband associations fire for
breakfast we're now in our 14th episode
of
2025 and before we kick off I'd like to
thank Wesco the Platinum sponsor of five
for
breakfast so I'm here in Philadelphia
with my good friends Rich Williams from
C2C and also the FBA um conference
program director and Evan Freeman who is
the uh FBA board member but he's also
the 2025 conference chair and we're
going to be doing a live semi 5 for
breakfast so please join us for this uh
you know speaking of Philadelphia the
reason we're in Philadelphia is we're
having our second um Regional fiber
connect um workshop and uh again sold
out so San Antonio was a home run just
you know set a record and we've um
meeted maximum capacity and filled out
there so it's great and then coming up
what's next is we'll be on uh fiber day
on the hill on April 9th in DC and we'll
be in the RoR room last year we had over
350 members of Congress their staff the
administration Niti FCC and it's just a
great way to remind our key policy
makers why it's so critical that we use
Fiverr for building out our nation's
broad critical Broadband
infrastructure um you know after um
fiber Dan Hill we'll be going down to
Nashville and that's what we're going to
be talking about a lot today is uh June
1st to Fourth is our fiber connect 2025
event and it's going to be epic that's
rich and um Evan what are you talking
about and then after um Nashville will
be an Anchorage in July Toronto and
August Spokane in September uh Scottdale
in October and Kansas City in November
and then we finish the year out in Palm
Springs for our Premier member meeting
from December 9th and 10th or excuse me
8th and 9th so that brings us today's
fire for breakfast session with Evan
Freeman and Rich Williams to talk about
our fireside chat on the fiber connect
2025 hot seat so last week on fire for
breakfast Our Guest was John Willow the
the co-founder of the community
Broadband Action Network or cband who
shared her insights on breaking barriers
using AI to develop uh connected
collaboration so um that was a really
interesting topic and if you missed it
you can go to our website and watch the
replay today in five breakfast I have
our our good friends Evan Freeman uh
who's on our board of directors and our
conference chair and Rich Williams who's
our program director to talk about our
fiber connect 2025 program the fiber
connect 2025 hot seat and they'll talk a
little bit why we call it a hot seat um
so Evan is the vice president of
government fairs and community relations
at EPB in Chattanooga in this role Evan
leads the epb's government relations and
economic development he served on the
fiber Broadband association's board and
the
2025 U fiber connect chairman and Rich
Williams is the president of connect 2
Communications PR agency he works with
clients on messaging program devel vment
and goals and with the team uh at
connect 2 to ensure programs develop uh
match clients priorities in this role at
FBA conference Pro um program director
he works with the executive team uh the
conference committee and other
stakeholders to craft and curate the
agendas for the regional fiber connnect
workshops and for our fiber connect
granddaddy um big conference so welcome
Evan and Rich hey G thanks for having us
yeah well just you know we've had so
much fun working over the past year on
this conference and this is going to be
our best year ever ever so why don't I
just turn over to you guys and you can
tell us a little bit about why this
conference is going to be better than
we've ever had I think it's interesting
the the the amount of time I I don't
think people understand the amount of
time it takes to prep for one of these
conferences when you have 5,000 of your
closest friends coming and you're trying
to shape the the the narrative and the
conversations so they're meaningful 12
month 12 months in advance you're sort
of making assumptions on things going to
happen um you know one of the things I
think was a bonus for us is a lot's
happened the last six months and you
know fiber connect really is a place if
you want to figure out how this impacts
your business come to fiber connect
because you we have all the people there
that give you the answers so it's going
be a really exciting show yep no we're
we're really excited about it and and um
you know last year was a very successful
show and and got a lot of great feedback
and and so a lot of the content that um
is pretty popular we're bringing back
again this year but but adding some some
new things to it as well well that's
kind I think the big challenge is when
you've had such a great show last year
how do we take it up to the next level
it was it was um nerve-wracking honestly
because you had this is a great show
you're like well how do we top that and
so we really went to the well and how do
we top that and and I sort of joke with
the staff about this all the time is I'm
you know I'll give you 100 ideas and 90
of them will suck um but 10 will be
pretty good and of those maybe like T
may be generous it t maybe generous but
but four of them just only four of them
are feasible but like we had our
planning meeting um
and the scary part is we had a bunch of
ideas and we're doing all of them and
I'm like holy moly we're doing all of
them so there's so there's so much
that's new there's so much that's been
fine-tuned um you we've added components
the popular ponents we've added depth to
it um we've created new things that we
think are important to the community
that that we're going to do for the
first time and if they work we'll bring
them back if not we'll find something
different but we're really excited about
about what we have in store for you as
we light it up at fiber connect yeah so
talk about that why so um provide L
Insight on light it up yeah well we we
came with the the Light It Up theme this
year is because we're really thinking
about um last year you know the
conversation was was heavy on on the
beat funding that was coming down um but
this year we're really thinking about um
not just the B funding but if you think
about a lot of our members the big
announcements that you talk about with
the capex that they're investing in
building fiber throughout the country
and so this year is really going to be a
significant year where networks are
being light up and rural areas that have
never been covered and served in a
meaningful way are going to be served
and and so that's that's where we're a
basis of the the theme of light it up
I'm so really excited about that you
know when we were meeting in October
last year to really set this tone for
the conference what we we thought it was
going to be this is going to be a
pivotal moment in history and we want to
make sure that everybody who comes to
the conference you know it's like
Alabama football right they say well
I'll go to the national championship
game next year you know because they
just think that they just going to have
this great conference every year and we
don't want people to get in that mod we
want to people don't want to miss
2025 right because it is the year that
we're going to be lighting things up and
do you guys want to walk through some of
the what you what's going to be going on
at the event yeah sure absolutely yeah I
think it's important to lay out just you
know to your point with the the football
announ ology like that this has been a
successful event but one of the reasons
that fiber connect has continually
gotten better every year is that we
think about how can we create recreate
ourselves and not just s stick with the
status quo to be better well and also
make sure the conversations are about
things are important in industry and not
have conversations where people are just
talking about their companies right like
we really eliminated that ability that
when you go to conferences you hear
people talk about just their products
like if you want to do that buy you you
can book space on the expool stage
otherwise it's about meaningful things
in the in the market yep and just
jumping right in talk you know something
for everyone um and again one of the
things that we want to do uh to be able
to to to continue to grow our conference
is is have something for everyone in in
the industry and in their companies and
so with that you know having the the 10
different content specific things like
the state Broadband Summit uh the sea
sleep Summit which is specifically
geared towards the SE sea Suite level
and and and the content and just the uh
really excited about that one cu the
environment in there um there's going to
be a sea Suite lounge and so it's really
an opportunity for those folks to come
in and they could they could do their
business there do set meetings there U
you know if they have have a cocktail
have some coffee right you got a Bria
there well this is networking you know
when I like think about the sea Suite
Summit you know specifically you know
we've been working really hard to try to
hone that in so that it this becomes a
really great environment for the
executive team from All Our member
companies and everybody in the industry
to be able to show up and one if you're
you know if you're a CEO of a company
you got to be able to have an
environment where you can continue to
work and run your business so we have
the meeting rooms and try to have the
lounge but also you want to be able to
meet with your peers and that's again
you know being able to have a networking
Lounge that you can have you know a
snack and be able to chat with your
friends but then also to have the C
sweet Forum so that we bring in um some
folks they might not have access to and
be able to have those conversations with
125 other CEOs and Senior Executives and
then we've created we've now this year
we're going to have some networking
right afterwards so that those
conversations can move forward yeah
absolutely and we also have the tribal
Broadband networking lounge and the
state bro stop State Broadband officer
or office networking lounge and i' you
know I've been talking to a lot of State
broadband directors and they're really
excited about you know because while
they're you know each state is kind of
doing their own thing they like to be
able to you know collaborate with their
colleagues around the nation and these
kind of opportunities where they can
spend time in the you know State
Broadband Office lounge to you know
coordinate and to you know run ideas by
their other Broadband directors is a
great opportunity yeah I'm super excited
about the tribal Broadband as well we're
still you know we've been trying to amp
that up and I think you this is really
going to be a big breakup for us this
year and tribal is doing some really
cool things it is and we've got tribal
content throughout the conference so
from um on the main stage from the
public the Broadband policy Symposium to
its own track and the breakouts on
Monday afternoon so a lot of tribal
content so if that's something that is
important to your business either as a
tri tribal Broadband um operator or um
tribal Nation or you're an operator that
wants to sell into that market this is
the place to
come um and along the lines of the the
networking um just bringing back the the
meetups um that we're going to have like
after so I think one of the things that
folks find most valuable it's just an
opportunity to go and and meet new
people that are in in the industry and
and you know that they can relate to we
have the the fiber under 40 um which has
been growing a whole lot we're excited
about that so I'm almost out of that one
I'm almost timed out of that um but but
quite a few meetups and and so I really
encourage folks to continue to to to be
a part of those and and really get to
know each other well that's funny cuz
like you know at the regional events
we've started doing new member meetups
and new members old members everybody
shows up um tonight we had one of those
and it's just a party and uh it's
exciting to see how much energy and how
people want to come in early to be able
to spend time and get to know other
members of the industry so it's it's
kind of contagious I think one things
that's happened is that these Regional
events and the main show they become the
place where business gets done right and
when you have the CEO of a company and
you have the CTO and you have the sales
people and you have the product people
they can have all the conversations they
need to have to move their business
forward so instead of just being a place
where you sort of interact and then
follow up deals are done at Fiverr
connect and that's you know that's sort
of a rare commodity of a or attribute of
a conference and that's one of the
things I think so exciting just you know
like being you and I in the green room
all three of us in the Green Room a lot
just hearing the people have
conversations that haven't met before
and saying oh we got to do this oh if
you thought about this it's just those
time those type of like side
conversations are gold yeah you know
that's one of my favorite things about
the position we're in is that we get to
connect people that you know two amazing
people in an industry that never met and
just allow them to and be there to
witness that conversation that you know
kind of gets elevated to the next level
yeah pretty cool yeah and just adding
about that like I I think uh you know us
being here in Philly like it's it's
interesting the amount of people that
are this is their first FBA event that
they've attended and so you know they
they've been doing the job maybe not a
long time some folks have been doing it
a long time but they've kind of been
isolated in their in their area and
their Zone and so they're not really
hearing from what's going around in
other areas and so this really um this
and fiber connect is a really great
opportunity for for to grow incitement
with them just to to show that like hey
that there is validation in what you
have been doing and here are some new
new things you may learn and may be able
to share with
others and got talking about the Expo
the expo hall yeah the expo hall really
exciting like over 50,000 Square ft of
exp expo hall space um over 300
exhibitors um it's it's pretty exciting
and and just going down to the XO Hall
um it it's pretty exciting it's it's a
massive display um and and really great
to see the energy down there and just
the again the networking and and
business that's getting done uh at the
expo hall and then this year we're doing
a couple new things we're doing the
smart home um Expo um so to to be able
to walk through and and see some of the
Smart Home Products that that are
available and so that feeds back into
you have fiber you have connectivity you
have uh the Broadband uh speed at home
that fiber brings so what what can you
do with it and so here are some you know
devices thermostats things like that and
then the opop PAC Rodeo which is which
is going to be exciting first time we're
doing that yeah yeah not your normal
radio no there but really really great
for you know just to put out there and
and uh show the Workforce Development
opportuni well this is kind of the the
big breakout for Workforce Development
you know as funding starts to flow and
and we're starting to move that's where
you know we're starting to see a big
uptick in the need for Workforce
Development so I think the the breakout
Rodeo the Workforce Development Rodeo
optic path Rodeo would be fantastic it's
a great place for the graduates of the
program to Showcase their skills so and
then of course because we're Nashville
we've got great music again throughout
the conference you know we kick off with
the the welcome party um we have uh
Sophia Scott who is this you know rising
star in Nashville she's got hitu here on
the radio she's playing the opening um
party you don't want to miss that from 5
to se 5:30 to 7: on Sunday we've got an
amazing um Dive Bar Koke party on Monday
night and a light it up um party Tuesday
night we've got amazing musicians
playing the main stage on Monday Tuesday
Wednesday um and just amazing stuff and
then we also have an exclusive first
look of the thought wav documentary yeah
was there a slide in that or there is
we'll talk a little bit more than a
second but we'll have that on Monday
night um it's going to be amazing it'll
be popcorn um but it's a documentary
that we'll talk a little bit about more
later but that's something you want to
put on your calendar to be there for and
the last thing is um oh just star power
so one of the things again and this one
was not my idea so I'm not at all
stealing the credit of the person who
had this idea but it was not me um I
don't have the permission to say their
name on on this broadcast so I won't
David um but they uh is we have Sean
Evans from the um hot ones coming to do
the fiber broad the fiber Hot Seat um at
live on stage at fiber connect um and so
should have done a sample for breakfast
today oh that would have been good we
should have done this here yeah mock it
up yeah um e progressively hotter ring
wings and and answer pointed questions
about what's happening in the Broadband
industry so we're excited about that
we're bringing some star power to the
stage
yeah so Sean Evans is a guy that he
feeds you hot wings and you answer hard
questions he does yeah he's said
everyone from presidents to to uh movie
stars to
musicians it's it's a it's a huge
YouTube show that um he sells his own
hot sauce apparently but it's a big
thing which only you know Echoes the
star power that you bring with a Live
recorded five breakfast that you do on
the main stage that that we do build as
a state uh an homage to the Between Two
Ferns So He surround you with like
hundreds Ferns and well I was just
thinking on the on the hot ones uh your
former employee Taylor do not go
head-to-head with her on hot sauce I
lost that one but she is coming to fiber
this year she did with my favorite
branded panel mother mayor I deploy
fiber which I can never say we have
three mayors that will Jo right she
works for a mayor now yeah yeah she's
coming back all right great and then get
get into it like who's going to be there
and and really the the um fiber
ecosystem and again we try to go and get
you know the the folks that are going to
be doing it in the state and so our
state Broadband office we have over um I
know over 22 State Broadband offices
confirmed to 10 uh we're still working
on on others and I know they're going to
be uh getting in there but the you know
having that state Broadband um space for
them last year was really helpful
because they they really truly did get
get to connect people with their state
and they can go and have side
conversation and sit down and really get
to know each other um and so really
bringing that back I think is going to
encourage more more of those what I love
about having the state Broadband
directors there is it's really an
opportunity for us to celebrate them and
all the hard work they've done to put
these State programs together and it's a
lot of hard work and you know I I just
really one I want to show our
appreciation for everything to do but
also for our attendees it's a great way
to um be able to spend time and to you
know you can cover a lot of states in
one day and um get a you know just learn
a lot about how you know is if you're
deploying in a multi-state um Network
it's really good to be able to have
those relationships and be able to spend
a little bit time with these Broadband
directors yeah and they're excited about
coming so it should be good yeah exactly
um and we'll also have uh you know
another key factor is Network operators
and and so you know we have over 275
speakers and um over 85 of those are
going to be Network Network operators
and and hearing from what's going on
from um you know providers like like us
um and and others just to hear you know
what what are what they're experiencing
what their plans are to build out and
and the the cool thing about hearing
from Network operators is really the
Innovation that's happening uh because
our country is so big and the the
terrain is so different and everybody's
really approaching deploying their fiber
in a different way and so it's it's
pretty interesting to hear from from a
good good cross-section of folks um and
then we also have a lot of think tanks
coming like PE Pew um charitable trust
is is a group that is not not strangers
to fiber connect uh they've come down
quite a bit Catherine's good friends
yeah cather's good friends and so really
excited to um to have her be a part of
it and then um you know important uh
part of it is is having the media
Spotlight and so we we have a pretty
great media turnout um that's in the
Broadband industry and and so we expect
seems like last year we had around 60
analyst love more this year we already
more more and I think they really
appreciate the fact that you guys run a
great Press Room and allows you
attendees that have new interesting
things to talk about and share with the
press to get those interviews and for
them to reach a lot of our members and
people in the industry well we we
actively encourage the members to have
news because there's so many journalists
attending because it it's symbiotic
relationship they have to have news the
reporters can write about um they
certainly get great content from
watching the the sessions but um but
having news is important to them too so
well you know my favorite thing is the
light talks Network operator light talk
yeah so I mean just having the CEOs and
top Executives from some of the leading
Broadband providers to get up and talk
about some interesting topics whether
it's deployment challenges or just
overall strategy or just how they're
really approaching this Market is to me
really insightful and I think we provide
a fantastic platform for a CEO at any
level company to come because our stage
is going to be fantastic this year it's
going to be epic it's it's it's one of
the yeah I guess it's really hard to
explain how how great it's going to be
um and really proud of of of uh what's
going on there and and it's just going
to be really really exciting bring a lot
of energy well I mean we're going to
have a massive LED wall it's the
state-ofthe-art our av company just has
all this brand new stateoftheart
um you know LED screening that's going
to be incredible plus our whole AV setup
is really we really amped up because
we're not just being able to you know
let people show PowerPoints but we're
really creating a theater effect and we
have live entertainment so this all has
to be you know professional quality and
so it's I think for any presenter you
know if you're a CEO of a large company
or even a small company to be able to
stand on the stage with um you know I
call it Oscar quality production oh
absolutely absolutely I mean it's
actually where we're going to debut um
the new tomorrow starts Year song the uh
song about the impact fiber has on
communities and how it helps build we um
we were inspired by one of our members
who woke up with a dream and went to
chat GPT and asked them to write
something and I'm like wellit can't do
that so we hired two of our friends that
are that are songwriters that have
performed at fiber connect and they
wrote this amazing song called Tomorrow
uh
tomorrow oh my gosh what I said it and
went on my head um tomorrow starts here
that uh they'll debut live on stage on
Monday and um we'll have a version out
before that so people can hear it but
it's pretty exciting well it's kind of
neat we're in Nashville so of course
we're going to have singer songwriters
create our own music our own fiber
Connect Music and uh the whole audience
will be able to participate in this
it'll be great and we also got a
Representatives talking about tella
health and talking about Precision a and
talking about autonomous vehicles and um
we've got like I said three Mayors
including mayor of Danbury Connecticut
the mayor of West de Mo and the mayor of
Charlottesville um speaking so it's
really going to be just lots of
perspective lots of insights lots of
great information you can take back to
help inform your business and music so
again I think I talked about a little
bit but Sophia Scott amazing artist is
opening it up we've got the um so last
year I forget the name of the Audi Ryan
lkin played last year he was like the um
CMA artist of the year or something like
that his song the painter was nominated
for um song of the a um Cody Johnson
recorded it but he wrote it and so you
you got some amazing talent that people
up incomers that people so I mean to me
this is really one of the things that
sets fiber connect apart from any other
conference in the world the fact that we
do have live entertainment to really I
mean keep the energy up because we want
you know people are excited about um
what we're doing what we're
accomplishing you know this whole
industry you know I look at you know how
much time I have left in this industry
and I really am anxious to be able to
get everybody connected with fiber by
the end of the decade and just bringing
in Creative people these artists that
really kind of pump it up it just seems
like just adds an amazing element that
kind of do makes every moment memorable
right like we don't want you to come to
fiber connect and have a moment where
you don't experience something that
you're not seeing somewhere else right
so we really look at try and create once
you once you hit our door it's immersive
experience that that it's full of things
you didn't expect the thought waves
documentary so we had this idea um and
we were as we were planning fiber
connect and yeah you know a lot of
conversations on bead and and I was
thinking about this I was like it's not
it's not really about bead it's not
about the last three years because none
of this would impossible if it hadn't
been for 50 years of innovation creating
both fiber broadband and the internet
and all the people and stories and
effort and time and challenges these
people went through to create something
that allowed a program like be to Sol to
close the digital divide right and
there's lots of pivot Points in the
market that happen that these these
companies um evolved and and innovated
and passed regulations and laws and and
so we've spent the last several months
interviewing dozens of these people and
we've got more interviews over the next
two months and we are going to do an
exclusive first look of the docu short
at fiber connect and then do a panel
with some of our experts we interviewed
we we talked to vent surf we talked to
um Larry Irving to Blair Lan to um the
mayor of Charlottesville we talked to um
Dr Karen Ruban who's one of the Pioneers
in tellah health like all these great
people that that are sharing their
stories of what they did what they
thought they were doing um and you'll
see it first at fiber connnect but then
you'll see it next at hopefully film
festivals so we're pretty excited about
it well you know I tell you rich um this
documentary f documentaries genius and
um I don't use that term lightly because
um you know I've been you I got to be
stuck on a train for 10 hours and got to
listen to you know I was there for a lot
of the interviews but I got to watch the
raw footage from guys like Vin surf or a
je pie and you know the Blair 11 or you
know and it just or even Alan Davidson I
mean it's just amazing to listen to you
know vent surf talking about inventing
tcpip I mean it's it's crazy and uh
what's happened over the past you forget
about you know when you've had long
careers of all how all this stuff came
together and so I'm super excited about
thought waves and you know unveiling
this amazing documentary one of the
people we're talking to next month is
the woman who coined the phrase surf the
Internet her name is Jean Amore ply and
she's the net mom and she first was one
of the first people to introduce um
computers in the 80s to public libraries
and then the first to introduce internet
as a community anchor it just is I mean
just their stories and the it I just
you're gonna love it it's gonna be
amazing well you know it kind of
inspires me like I'll take Kevin my dog
for a walk and I'll listen to these
interviews and when you hear vent Surfer
Blair 11 talking about the moments and
time that changed everything you know
when Mark andreon created the browser
Mosaic browser that you can actually get
on the internet um the fact when the day
that Steve Jobs created the iPhone and
and now you know chat gbt and AI you
know you don't think about that being
another moment in time but we are at the
cusp of some really big things happening
no Nexus is something I'm really really
excited about because I love just when
it hasn't when you think it can't get
any better we had these ideas and we're
doing all of them so like's getting
better um you know really really a huge
Dolly Dolly Parton fan one from her
music but you know been being in
Tennessee and just the Legacy that she's
she's um built just as you know her
philanthropy and really caring and giv
it back to the community and so one of
one of her big projects is the
Imagination Library um which which for
folks that don't know you know for for
you know if you have a child
kindergarten through fifth grade I mean
I mean sorry uh from Z zero through five
yeah um you can get a free book in the
mail so you sign up and um you go to the
website you sign up and every month you
get a new book and it's a great
opportunity just saying you know talking
with them and learning about how the
literary literary scores have gone up
for not just the kids but for the
parents because this is an opportunity
for the parents to sit down and read and
some of these parents are learning to
read um proficiently um and so just that
that family bonding and and that
opportunity and so you ask hey what does
that have to do with like internet and
growing well to yeah everything so and
so for for families to be able to to use
the internet you know that being able to
being able to read being able to
interact together you think about
families um being involved with their
students um education and and homework
that's online and things like that so it
it's just it really is just a great
starting point for them to work together
and so with that we have uh NE mccauly
with um the Dollywood Foundation that's
going to come and speak to our women in
fiber luncheon and um actually some of
the proceeds of our ticket sales for
that is going to go towards the donation
to the imagination imagination library
and so really excited about that and
really really supporting to cause that
that Dolly's Champion not just in
Tennessee but all over the country it's
still growing 3 million books a month
Che so if you haven't signed up for
women in fiber lunch in at fber connect
whether you're a guy or girl please sign
up U as Evan said we're GNA have a huge
donation to that um cause from the
proceeds from that lunch in uh and again
dolly
is not not just music but her whole
personality her whole spirit is kind of
feels like the moment we're in time is
really to try to elevate the quality of
life for generations to come and that's
I think such a great fit between fiber
broadband and Dolly Parton and where
where we're trying to get the entire
energy industry and and we're excited
some more things too we'll announce
later on they're working on too so the
last day of the conference is the state
Broadband Summit and you don't want to
leave early because this is where you're
going to find out all the things you
need to know about bead are going to
happen here we've got five state barand
officers they'll be on a a state barand
panel we've got the three mayors that I
mentioned we've got um a really in-depth
panel with some experts as our um hosted
by Katie ESP from EPB um about outside
plant challenges um it's this going to
be a great last day but you definitely
don't want to miss that well rich and
Evan first of all I want to thank you
for the tremendously hard work you guys
have put in to be able to get our
conference and we have the deer and the
whole team behind you guys and David and
everybody that's been working on this
but this is going to be the best
conference in the world and I cannot
wait till June 1st to four so thank you
guys for all your hard work thanks for
sharing with our audience and I hope you
guys can get back together with us next
week we're going to be with Brian
Mitchell the Nevada state Broadband
director to talk about Nevada's gold
star Broadband plan so they are one of
the top two um top three states that
have been approved with their final
proposals for be and you're going to
want to hear from Brian so thanks
everyone we'll see you guys at fiber
connect June 1st through 4th and we'll
see you next week with Brian Mitchell